<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-10-13T02:13:54+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Panting Panda</title><subtitle>This is the official site of Panting Panda, the moniker of ambient/electronic composer Moniet Sawhney.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">JellyFlop (OST)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/audio/2017/09/10/JellyFlop.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="JellyFlop (OST)" /><published>2017-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-09-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/audio/2017/09/10/JellyFlop</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/audio/2017/09/10/JellyFlop.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Credits: Music Composition, Sound Design&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project was completed over four months, and was a complete blast for me.
I worked day in and out to get the tracks done, and loved every single minute. The compositions were recorded in the box (aka my bedroom), using industry standard microphones (AT-2050 and SM57), with the evergreen Steinberg ‘D-preamp’ interface which was also used for percussion samples and electric guitar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the SFX, I conducted field recordings for the game and processed them to de-noise, to get a clean sound.
Further, I combined this with audio synthesis to shape the FX in a full rich sound.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="audio" /><summary type="html">Credits: Music Composition, Sound Design</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why Music is a Practical Career</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2017/09/01/whymusicispractical.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why Music is a Practical Career" /><published>2017-09-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-09-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blogs/2017/09/01/whymusicispractical</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2017/09/01/whymusicispractical.html">&lt;p&gt;Music is often disregarded as an impractical in many families, perhaps because of the “you are something or you are nothing” philosophy that we keep hearing in the music industry. But I don’t believe that statement to be true. And here’s why:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrary to to popular belief, music has numerous revenue streams which will allow music professionals to earn a respectable living, and they are only growing in number especially with the advents of streaming (Universal Music claims to make 6M in revenues this year).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few examples of some of the ways to make money in music:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Music Education&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Music Therapy (a field with an increasing demand)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Music Journalism&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Music Blogging&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Social Media Management (for the various music studios and entertainment industries)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Working as an Arranger&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Freelance Composer for Film, Advertising or Video Games&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In house composer for advertising/video game agencies.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In house and freelance sound designer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Public Representative for labels (PR)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Band Manager&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Music Supervisor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blogs" /><summary type="html">Music is often disregarded as an impractical in many families, perhaps because of the “you are something or you are nothing” philosophy that we keep hearing in the music industry. But I don’t believe that statement to be true. And here’s why:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Women Of Music I Adore</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2017/08/31/WomenOfMusic.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Women Of Music I Adore" /><published>2017-08-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-08-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blogs/2017/08/31/WomenOfMusic</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blogs/2017/08/31/WomenOfMusic.html">&lt;p&gt;I was inspired to write this post because I feel like the only women I see being represented in social media are the big stars like Taylor Swift, Beyoncé, Katy Perry etc. Although I have nothing against these artists, and acknowledge the fact that they’re talented in their own right, I would still like to see more than just the one-off article on Pitchfork -for example- about the artists I’ve mentioned in the post.
 On the other hand, there are the &lt;strong&gt;WOMEN ONLY&lt;/strong&gt; curated playlists you so often find on streaming services like Spotify. The reason I’m not a big fan of them is because of the statement that kind of playlist is making. The statement saying “here’s a playlist you should listen to just because these songs were made by women”. And I think that it undermines them in a big way, as these are talented individuals who’ve put in artistic effort to produce excellent, professional records. And I think we should appreciate these women as we would any other artist of any gender, sexuality, and/or religion, i.e, for their art!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I’ve got that out of the way, here is a list of few of the women I’ve come to adore in the music industry, along with a few reasons why:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;elizabeth-morris&quot;&gt;Elizabeth Morris&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first encounter with Elizabeth Morris’ songwriting was through the final album release of the band &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/artist/0cygwaJypZFDlu4NLQTm7b&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Allo Darling’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in which she sang, and played the ukulele. I was fortunate enough to have randomly picked up &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/1FosDgVaOv7qsZt9k56o1s&quot;&gt;the LP&lt;/a&gt;  at a local record store, and I fell in love with the record ever since my first listen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, Morris’s writing is honest, innocent, and incredibly relatable. From sappy romantic to contemplative, Morris’s writing is such that it struck a chord with me (pun intended) at every turn, and made me have to take hours off work to ponder about life, to introspect, and to appreciate the people I’ve been fortunate to have in my life. And I always love a record that does that, who doesn’t?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I admire the most about Elizabeth is the simplicity, not only in her writing, but also in the way she puts chords together on a ukulele. She can make a simple 1-4-1 progression incredibly effective through her sweet melodies, and often touching lyrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sophie-allison&quot;&gt;Sophie Allison&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a fan of home studios and bedroom production, I was bound to fall in love with Sophie Allison, aka &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/artist/4wXchxfTTggLtzkoUhO86Q&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Soccer Mommy’s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, music from the very first listen of her latest record &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/1NcmOmza86zn7wt02k9q74&quot;&gt;Collection&lt;/a&gt; (which I highly recommend if you like bedroom pop). Like her &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/0WtsLEGmrrEc1TfGeyLi1N&quot;&gt;previous album&lt;/a&gt;, Collection has a raw and minimalistic approach to it, as you can clearly hear in the songs &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/05SS1T78bHkLPEb9VTvEoE&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;“3 AM at a Party”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/4cJjMJ2fMA7edeEI1xbVFO&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Waiting for Cars”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, where it’s mostly just her voice in sung unison with each other and a guitar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her music is dynamic, and can be melancholic and energetic at the same time. What I like most about her music is how it flows through so many sections, and how she’s able to transition from one catchy guitar intro, and convert it completely in the pre-chorus and choruses following it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in   all, &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/track/3B0vMz20sN9UUwAwcP2QGQ&quot;&gt;Allison’s&lt;/a&gt; music is a fun combination of good ol’ rock song forms, minimal (but effective) use of instrumentation, heavyhearted and personal lyrics, a remarkably unique voice, and a perfect guitar tone!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="blogs" /><summary type="html">I was inspired to write this post because I feel like the only women I see being represented in social media are the big stars like Taylor Swift, Beyoncé, Katy Perry etc. Although I have nothing against these artists, and acknowledge the fact that they’re talented in their own right, I would still like to see more than just the one-off article on Pitchfork -for example- about the artists I’ve mentioned in the post. On the other hand, there are the WOMEN ONLY curated playlists you so often find on streaming services like Spotify. The reason I’m not a big fan of them is because of the statement that kind of playlist is making. The statement saying “here’s a playlist you should listen to just because these songs were made by women”. And I think that it undermines them in a big way, as these are talented individuals who’ve put in artistic effort to produce excellent, professional records. And I think we should appreciate these women as we would any other artist of any gender, sexuality, and/or religion, i.e, for their art!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">One Hell of a Week (OST)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/audio/2017/08/27/ohw.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="One Hell of a Week (OST)" /><published>2017-08-27T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-08-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/audio/2017/08/27/ohw</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/audio/2017/08/27/ohw.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Credits: Music Composition for Levels&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This theme was a blast to work on! My task was to compose songs for different levels and have them weave into each other seamlessly, which I accomplished thanks to Ableton Live, and its wonderfully easy methods to loop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the project, my hands were busy programming the synthesizers.
I chose the synthesizer as it never fails to fit in perfectly with the aesthetics of mobile app games.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="audio" /><summary type="html">Credits: Music Composition for Levels</summary></entry></feed>